Finding Aid to the Save the Redwoods League photograph collection. 1885-2014
The Bancroft Library
Save the Redwoods League photograph collection.
1885-2014
circa 1920-2000
BANC PIC 2006.030
Save the Redwoods League
approximately 16,000 photographs 28 digital objects (28 images)
The Bancroft Library University of California, Berkeley Berkeley, CA 94720-6000 Phone: (510) 642-6481 Fax: (510) 642-7589 Email: bancref@library.berkeley.edu
Information for Researchers
Access
COLLECTION STORED, IN PART, OFF-SITE: Advance notice required for use.
NEGATIVES: RESTRICTED. Available for use by appointment only.
NITRATE NEGATIVES (NNEG boxes): CLOSED TO RESEARCH DUE TO HAZARDOUS MATERIALS RESTRICTIONS.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital reproductions of selected images are available.
Related Material
Save the Redwoods League records, 1854-2013, BANC MSS 88/15 c
Portraits of Save the Redwoods League members, BANC PIC 1988.040--PIC
Photographs taken for the Union Lumber Company about 1921 [i.e. 1921-1924] showing cutting, second-growth, and reforestation, Redwood region, f F868.M5 U6
Views of redwood trees, BANC PIC 1960.013--AX
In memory of the brothers Drury: Newton and Aubrey, BANC PIC 1979.066--ALB
Separated Material
The following items were transferred to the Audio-visual Collections of the Bancroft Library:
"Bulldozed America," CBS Reports television episode, 1965, Motion Picture 1415 C
"War in the Redwoods," Assignment Four, KRON (television station) editorial, 1964, Motion Picture 1416 C
"Commemoration Rotary Memorial Grove, RC Eureka, CA meeting, R King speaker," September 16, 2002, Motion Picture 1417 D
Conservation of natural resources -- California; Coast redwood -- California -- Pictorial works; Logging--California -- Pictorial works; National parks & reserves -- California; Redwoods--California; State parks & reserves -- California; Landscape photographs; Save-the-Redwoods League; Del Norte County (Calif.); Humboldt County (Calif.); Marin County (Calif.); Mendocino County (Calif.); Monterey County (Calif.); San Mateo County (Calif.); Santa Cruz County (Calif.); Sonoma County (Calif.); Calaveras County (Calif.); Tuolumne County (Calif.)
Administrative Information
Arrangement
The collection is arranged thematically in 8 series: Series 1: Vertical Files; Series 2: Humboldt County Photographic Survey; Series 3: Albums (boxed); Series 4: Postcards; Series 5: Save the Redwoods League Officers; Series 6: Photographer Files; Series 7: Miscellaneous Negatives and Lantern Slides; Series 8: Miscellany.
The Save the Redwoods League is a non-profit organization, established in 1918, whose mission "is to protect and restore redwood forests and connect people with their peace and beauty so these wonders of the natural world flourish." (from Save the Redwoods League website, 2016.)
This collection chiefly consists of photographs (approximately 9,700 photographic prints, 5,400 negatives, and 1,000 slides) of redwood trees, forests and parks in coastal Northern California, as well as giant sequoia trees in the Sierra Nevada area, taken by, taken for, or collected by, Save the Redwoods League staff and members to support its mission. There is additional pictorial material relating to the League itself. Of note are images of League official and National Parks Director Newton B. Drury, photographs of California Governors Edmund G. Brown and Ronald Reagan, U.S. Presidents Herbert Hoover, Lyndon B. Johnson and Bill Clinton, First Lady Lady Bird Johnson, logging, grove dedications, Dawn Redwood at Mo-tao-chi in Central China, and highway and erosion studies in Northern California redwood country. Also includes posters that relate the age of redwood trees to events in history, and panoramic photographs.
Folders contain photographs (or prints of digital images) unless noted. Other material includes postcards, prints, posters, drawings, brochure and pamphlet samples, some documents, newsclippings, ceremonial pens and plaques.
Container Listing
- Series 1: Vertical Files., 1897-2014; cartons 1-8; A box 1; AX box 1, folders 1-20; B box 1, folders 1-15, 17-18; C box 1; D folder 1; F folder 1; H folder 1; NEG boxes 1-5; NEG(gl) boxes 1, 3, 8, 9; NNEG boxes 1-6
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Scope and Content of Collection
  Subject file that consists chiefly of material removed from file cabinets of Save the Redwoods League offices. The bulk of the material is photographic prints that range from snapshots taken by staff members to 8x10 prints and panoramas taken by professional photographers. Other kinds of non-photographic material included, such as posters, documents and newsclippings, are noted in the folder content notes.
  The bulk of the subjects include state parks, state recreation areas, and national parks, landscapes of redwood forests and watersheds, logging, scenic highways through the areas, dedication ceremonies, and visitors to the parks. There are also images related to the Save the Redwoods League organization and its leaders.
  Most locations are in California, especially Northern California. Major parks include Big Basin Redwoods State Park, Calaveras Big Trees State Park, Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park, Humboldt Redwoods State Park, Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, Redwood National Park, and Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Parks.
  Original alphabetical arrangement and folder heading descriptions from the file cabinet folders have largely been retained. Some folder headings have been changed by Bancroft Library staff for consistency, and to keep like subjects together. Some material not originally found in the vertical files, such as thin notebook type albums, have been filed here by Bancroft Library staff for researcher convenience. Oversize materials are described in this series as well. Subjects listed are 1 folder, unless otherwise noted.
  NITRATE NEGATIVES (NNEG boxes): CLOSED TO RESEARCH DUE TO HAZARDOUS MATERIALS RESTRICTIONS.
  - Adams, Ansel -- Sugar Pine., not after 1932 (Carton 1)
    Copy negative of image only. No photographic print available. Viewing copy (reference print out from copy negative) on file.
    Photograph took second prize in Save the Redwoods League photo completion, 1932.
    Copy negative of Sugar Pine photograph removed to NEG box 1.
  - Angel Island., circa 1950-1965? (Carton 1)
    Includes view of San Francisco from Angel Island.
  - Arcata Redwood Company lands., 1965-1972 (Carton 1)
    Includes clear cut areas, a logging exhibit and Emerald Creek.
    Includes photographs by Moulin Studios, Martin Litton and Howard King.
    1 related copy negative of clear cut area, photograph by Martin Litton, removed to NEG box 1.
  - Archer Taylor Preserve (land trust for Napa County), April 1998 (Carton 1)
    Color snapshots.
  - Armstrong Redwoods State Natural Reserve (Sonoma County)., circa 1920, 1961 (Carton 1)
    Includes Colonel Armstrong Tree.
    7 related negatives (numbered 29034 A-H) removed to NNEG box 1.
  - Ayer, Edward E., collection., 1919-1921 (Carton 1)
    A notebook of snapshots divided into five sections: redwoods, Eel River; redwoods, Muir Woods; redwoods, Big Basin; redwoods, Santa Cruz County Grove, big trees, Calaveras Grove, and big trees, Mariposa Grove. Includes people standing next to trees, cabins and automobiles.
    Duplicate prints in the form of modern contact sheets and item list are available in BANC PIC 2006.030--fALB v.9.
    74 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 1.
  - Ayer, Edward E., collection -- Negative sleeves., 1919-1921 (Carton 1)
    Empty annotated sleeves for negatives.
  - Bear Gulch., 1890-1966 (Carton 1)
    Earlier images are copy photographs.
  - Benbow Lake State Recreation Area (Humboldt County)., 1972 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by Howard King.
  - Bennett Juniper tree., July 31, 1989 (Carton 1)
    Color snapshots of Peter Brown and Ken Brunges taking core samples from the tree.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park (Santa Cruz County)., 1900-1985, undated; 2 folders (Carton 1)
    Includes Lincoln Hill' park ranger with visitors; Berry Creek area and maps. Trees include The Princess, The Chieftain, Father of the Forest, Fallen Monarch and Animal Tree. Groves include Y-1, Y-2, Y-3, Y-5, Y-20, Y-30, Y-32, Y-33, Y-34, Y-35, Y-38, Y-40, Y-42, Y-44, Y-46, Y-53, Y-57, Y-65, Y-71, Y-73, Y-81, Y-83, Y-88, Y-70 or 92; Susan H. and David L. Hirsch III Grove.
    Includes photographs by Angel, Edward and Mrs. Ayer, Pillsbury Pictures and Howard King.
    Originally known as California State Redwood Park.
    4 matching and 6 related copy negatives removed to NNEG box 1. 2 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park, oversize., 1924?, undated; 3 photographs (Ax box 1, Folder 1)
    Father of the Forest Tree (2 copies), larger duplicate shelved as oversize G; Andrew P. Hill Memorial Fountain.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park, oversize., circa 1920?; 1 photograph (B box 1, Folder 14)
    Animal Tree. Photograph by B. Janeith Knight.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park, oversize., 1976; 1 photograph: color (D folder 3)
    Susan H. and David L. Hirsch III Grove. Matted photograph by Howard King (number 22376-2).
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park, oversize., 1906; 3 photographs
    "The Mother of the Forest, California Redwood Park." Pillsbury Picture Co., S.F., no. 3039 (2 copies).
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park album., circa 1905-1925? (Carton 1)
    Notebook type album entitled, "Photographs in the Big Basin Area, California Redwoods Park." Incudes park entrance, post office, store, club house, inn, warden's office, campfire circle, Father Tree, Opal Creek and Ball Field.
    Bulk of photographs are by Angel.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Berry Creek and Waddle Creek areas., 1963-1976 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by Howard King and David Swanlund.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Grove Y-61., March 30, 1979 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by David Swanlund.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- King photograph album., 1963-1966; 10 photographs and 1 map (Carton 1)
    Notebook type album of photographs by Howard King.
    4 negatives (3 matching and 1 related) removed to NEG box 1.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Locatelli Property., 1966-1968 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Rancho del Oso Nature and History Center. (Carton 1)
    Color photographs of the dioramas.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Santa Cruz Lumber Company property., January 1971 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Storm damage., January 1974 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Tibbitts photographs., circa 1915-1925 (Carton 1)
    Includes Santa Clara Tree, people driving through park, and campsite in Boulder Creek.
    - "Camping in California State Redwoods Park near Boulder Creek, Calif.", [1920s?]; Tibbitts, H. C.; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 1)
      Numbered 25438.
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- Tibbitts photographs.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 71-500., December 1971 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 72-500., 1972 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 73-500., 1973 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 74-500., 1974 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by Howard King. Folder contains 1 item.
    Folder contains 1 item.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 76-500., 1976 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 77-500., 1977 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 79-500., 1979 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 79-501., 1979 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 84-500., 1984 (Carton 1)
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 85-500., 1985 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by Don Briggs.
  - Big Basin Redwoods State Park -- 03-002., October 4, 2003 (Carton 1)
    Snapshots of a tour group in the park.
  - Big Creek (Monterey County)., 1946-circa 1975 (Carton 1)
    Includes color slides of Farr property.
  - Big Lagoon, Harry Merlo State Recreation Area (Humboldt County)., 1938-1974, undated (Carton 1)
    Includes Big Lagoon Timber property formerly owned by the Louisiana Pacific Corp.
    Includes photographs by Howard King.
  - Big Lagoon, Harry Merlo State Recreation Area -- Johnson photographs., May 1997 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by Evan Johnson.
  - Big Lagoon, Harry Merlo State Recreation Area -- Swanlund photographs., 1974-1982 (Carton 1)
    Includes aerial view photographs by David Swanlund.
  - Bookmarks with redwood forest images., after 1963 (Carton 1)
    Includes photographs used for bookmarks and finished bookmarks.
  - Briggs, Don, 1985-1988 (Carton 1)
    Documentation related to Navarro and Little Sur photographs. No photographs included.
    For related photographs by Don Briggs, see the Photographer Files.
    4 negatives removed to NEG box 4.
  - Burl photographs., 1963-1965 (Carton 1)
    Redwood trees with burls. Locations include Bull Creek Flat and Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park.
    Photographs by David Swanlund and Moulin Studios.
  - Butano State Park (San Mateo County)., circa 1937-2004? (Carton 1)
    Includes Butano Falls and Creek.
    Includes photographs by Moulin and Hanson, and snapshots by Ruskin Hartley.
  - Butano State Park album., 1938, undated (Carton 1)
    Notebook type album entitled, "Butano Redwoods (adjoining Big Basin Redwoods State Park in Santa Cruz and San Mateo Counties)." Includes Silver Falls and Golden Falls of Berry Creek, and part of Berry Creek in Big Basin Redwoods State Park.
    Includes photographs by Moulin and Hanson.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park (Calaveras and Tuolumne Counties)., circa 920s-1984 (Carton 1)
    Includes the Stanislaus River.
    2 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 3.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- Gutteridge photographs., 1953 (Carton 1)
    Photographs by John E. Gutteridge.
    26 matching and 2 related negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park – Hotel and buildings., 1874-1967 (Carton 1)
    Includes photograph of the Calaveras Big Trees Hotel by Watkins (modern copy print only) and dance hall constructed on a tree stump.
    1 matching copy negative removed to NEG box 1.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- National Geographic trip., 1950 (Carton 1)
    North and South Groves. Some images published in National Geographic in 1951.
    Includes photographs by Raymond Moulin.
    22 matching color transparencies removed to NEG box1.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- North Grove., circa 1920-1981
    Includes Empire State Tree and Mother of the Forest tree (formerly "the world's largest sugar pine").
    Includes photographs by Lawton, Winfield Scott and William Schoeb.
    5 matching copy negatives removed to NEG box 1. 4 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 2.
    - "Pioneers Cabin, Calaveras Grove of Big Trees California.", BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 1)
      Young man on horseback seen through hole cut into base of sequoia tree, Calaveras Big Trees State Park.
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- North Grove.
    - "In the Calaveras North Grove.", circa 1920s?; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 1)
      Four people standing at the base of a sequoia tree.
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- North Grove
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- North and South Grove photographs by David Swanlund., June 1982 (Carton 1)
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- South Grove., 1920s-1967 (Carton 1)
    Includes Sentinel Tree, South Grove dedication, Newton B. Drury, M.F. Small and Fred Meyer.
    Some photographs by Bob Hooe, and 1 photograph attributed to Ansel Adams.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- South Grove -- Aerial views., 1950 (Carton 1)
    US Navy official photographs by Cor. H.R. Swenson.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- South Grove photographs by Sheldon Davis., 1924-circa 1926 (Carton 1)
    Includes Horace M. Albright, Francis P. Farquhar, Edgar Whiteside, Arthur Roberts, Colonel John R. White and Elmer Reynolds on a visit to the grove. Bulk are modern copy prints.
    12 copy negatives made from glass negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Calaveras Big Trees State Park -- Visitor Center., 1983 (Carton 1)
    Includes construction of visitor center, and offices in building. Photographs by Pail A.E. Moeller.
  - California Academy of Sciences., 1920-1948 (Carton 1)
    Includes dioramas and exhibits as well as staff creating exhibits, Dr. Earl S. Herald, visitors and man working with geology samples.
    12 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 3. 1 related negative of a child looking at a cross section of a tree removed to NNEG box 2.
  - Cannon photographs., 1922-1925 (Carton 1)
    Snapshots mentioned in a letter from Dr. W.A. Cannon. According to note with photos, they are related to reforestation. Includes redwood forests in Humboldt County and a tree nursery at Fort Bragg. Locations include Mill Creek, near Dyerville, Bull Creek Flat, cabin near South Fork. Bulk are by Dr. Cannon, some taken by Ellsworth.
  - Carter Property at Grizzly Creek., 2003 (Carton 1)
    Includes property description and map used for fund raising to purchase property.
  - Cartoons., 1967, undated (Carton 1)
    Copies of cartoons. No original cartoons present.
    3 copy negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Cartoons, oversize., 1902; 1 print: color (C box 1, Folder 1)
    The Eighth Wonder of the World (centerpiece from Judge magazine). Color lithograph by Flohri.
  - Cascade Ranch, San Mateo County., circa 1970s-1990s (Carton 1)
    1 35mm negative strip with 2 matching copy negatives removed to NEG box 2.
  - Castle Rock State Park -- McMullen Property., 1980 (Carton 1)
    Photograph by Howard King.
  - Certificate of appreciation to Save-the-Redwoods League from National Park Service, Western Regional Office., 1987 (Carton 1)
    25 matching negatives (35mm strips) removed to NEG box 2.
  - Coast Dairies State Park (Santa Cruz County)., 1 photograph (F folder 1)
    Aerial view of coast.
  - Cook Property, Humboldt County., circa 1980s-1990s (Carton 1)
    Color snapshots of area near Humboldt Lagoons State Park.
    23 matching and related 35mm negatives removed to NEG box 2.
  - Corridor from the Redwoods to the Sea, Johnson photographs., May 2000 (Carton 1)
    Contact sheets and larger prints of selected images of event. Photographs by Evan Johnson.
    107 matching and related negatives, and 236 matching and related 35mm color slides in NEG box 6.
  - Corridor from the Redwoods to the Sea, Thorn photographs., 2000? (A box 1)
    Photographs by Doug Thorn of Gilham Butte area, and an article from California Wild.
    Several photographs were formerly with Evan Johnson photographs of Corridor from the Redwoods to the Sea.
  - Council Madrone., 1941-2002, undated (Carton 1, 2 folders)
    Coast madrone tree near Ettersburg, Humboldt County. Tree fell in 2000.
    11 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1. 26 matching negatives removed to NEG box 2. 1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 2.
  - Crater Lake., August 16, 1933 (Carton 1)
  - Daily Grove., circa 2000 (Carton 2)
  - Dawn Redwood (Metasequoia)., 1948 (Carton 2)
    Redwood tree at Mo-tao-chi in Central China worshiped as a tree god. Building at base is a temple. Photograph by Ralph W. Chaney. Folder contains 1 item.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park (Del Norte County)., circa 1920s-1961 (Carton 2)
    Includes coastal and redwood views, Old Redwood Highway, Grant Grove, McMeekan Tract and False Klamath Cove.
    Includes photographs by Russell Angel, Martin and Moulin Studios.
    2 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park, oversize., circa 1920, 1966; 3 photographs (Ax box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes trail through the alders in the J.D. Grant Grove, by Russell Angel (number 5260). Rhododendrons in Mary Prentice Huntington Grove, by Howard King.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park, oversize., May 1974, 1981; 2 photographs: color (D folder 4)
    Matted photograph by Larry Ulrich (number LU 574-8). Matted photograph by David H. Swanlund.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- King photographs., 1965-1972 (Carton 2)
    Photographs by Howard King. Includes the Mac and Gertrude McKee Grove, Gold Bluff Beach and False Klamath Cove.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- Rhododendron., 1966, undated (Carton 2)
    Includes photographs by David Swanlund and Howard King, and snapshots.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- Swanlund photographs., 1965-1966 (Carton 2)
    Photographs by David Swanlund. Includes a truck camper on the Old Redwood Highway.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- Ulrich photographs., 1974-1983 (Carton 2)
    Photographs by Larry Ulrich.
    1 matching 8x10 color transparency (2 copies) removed to NEG box 4.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- 33-500., 1933 (Carton 2)
    Anson Grove. Folder contains 1 item.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- 42-500., 1942 (Carton 2)
    Rhododendron in J.D. Grant Grove. Photograph by Moulin Studios. Folder contains 1 item.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- 66-500., 1966 (Carton 2)
    Includes photographs by Howard King, Moulin Studios and David Swanlund.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- 69-500., 1969 (Carton 2)
    Includes photographs by Howard King and David Swanlund.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- 97-500., 1997 (Carton 2)
    Includes redwood forests and rhododendron. All are photographs by Evan Johnson.
  - Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park -- 02-003., 2002 (Carton 2)
    Snapshots of trail through groves.
    25 matching negatives (35mm negative strips) removed to NEG box 2.
  - Del Norte County., 1925-1945, undated (Carton 2)
    Includes A.D. Lee's Giant Redwood, Knapp Hospital in Crescent City, and Rust Tract.
    Includes photographs by Patterson, Emerson Knight, Moulin Studios and McCurry Foto Co.
    6 related negatives of coastal scenes, Bertsch estate and Howe property) removed to NNEG box 2. 4 negatives (2 matching and 2 related) of Kapp Hospital removed to NNEG box 3.
  - Dewitt, John B., Secretary and Executor Director, Save-the-Redwoods League., 1968, undated (Carton 2)
    Includes John B. Dewitt and office staff at a Save-the-Redwoods League Semi-Centennial ceremony, June 15, 1968.
  - Dimitroff sketches., May 1965 (Neg box 1)
    6 negatives of sketches by Lucienne Bloch Dimitroff. Subjects include landscapes, trees and plants. No prints available.
  - Drury, Newton B., 1920-1973; 2 folders (Carton 2)
    Includes Portraits of Newton B. Drury, dedication at Mill Creek, Drury being sworn in as Director of National Park Service, Drury receiving check from Mrs. Robert Homans of the Hillsborough Garden Club, National Parks Advisory Board tour of the redwoods, Ronald Reagan and Drury at presentation of funds to California for the acquisition of Pepperwood Forest, and Stewart Udall presenting the Department of Interior's Conservation Service Award to Drury.
    20 copy negatives (19 matching and 1 related) removed to NEG box 1. 1 matching 8x10 copy negative removed to NEG box 4.
    - Presentation to Governor Ronald Reagan of California of $7 million for Pepperwood Grove addition to Humboldt Redwoods State Park., March 13, 1968; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 2)
      Governor Ronald Reagan, State Assemblyman Frank Belotti, Resources Administrator Norman B. Livermore, Secretary of Save the Redwoods League Newton B. Drury, State Senator Randolph Collier, President of Save the Redwoods League Ralph Chaney, Assistant to the Secretary of Save the Redwoods League John B. Dewitt.